♪I lean and gaze at misty waves afar♪
♪Tears fall on the ancient road
'neath the setting sun♪
♪One lone shadow on the cold river♪
♪In dreams, I return to the old window♪
♪Mountains stretch, the road home fades♪
♪A flute cries out, hooves hurry on♪
♪My heart adrift beneath a frosted moon♪
♪Drinking alone, I mourn our parting♪
♪Night turns cold, wind stirs the veil♪
♪Old robes recall forgotten days♪
♪Heart sore, a lone goose flies south♪
♪Where shall I send this letter?♪
♪Lost in thought through endless nights♪
♪Love runs deep, dreams linger on♪
♪Only sorrow remains♪
♪A cup of wine, my shadow makes us two♪
♪Drunk and lost through flashing blades♪
♪I curse how swiftly the years pass by♪
♪The wandering road goes on♪
♪Desolate, time frosts my youthful hair♪
♪Through the years, love still burns♪
♪A thousand tears fall♪
♪Worlds apart, tears stain my sleeves♪
♪Old dreams haunt my heart,
tears cloud my eyes♪
♪Heartbroken, soul-worn,
pain won't fade♪
♪Moonlight westward, the night drags on♪
♪The years have left their scars♪
♪Autumn winds sweep leaves;
shadows pair♪
♪The past fades like smoke;
tears fall♪
♪My heart lies broken♪
♪Lost in thought through endless nights♪
[Love Legend]
[Episode 18]
Come here.
Shandou.
Wait here for me, okay?
Okay.
Little girl.
What are you eating?
Could you
give me one?
Thanks.
There's one more thing
I need to report.
What is it?
These rebels
have hideouts everywhere.
The court has sent troops many times,
but still can't find their base.
But,
I didn't let you down.
I found their base.
Perhaps Your Highness could
give me the cure first,
and free me
from this Gu inside me.
Then I can
leave at once
and capture the rebels.
That depends
on how useful you are.
Your Highness.
When I was young,
I worked at the Ministry of Works.
One year, there was a severe drought.
While searching for water,
well,
I've covered
every inch of land
of the capital.
Myrtle berries of this color
grow in only
one place.
And that's
Shanhua Valley.
Well,
you really do know your stuff.
To serve you,
I'd gladly give my life.
Then die.
You're nothing but a tool.
How dare you bargain with me?
Guards.
Send my order.
The rebels
assassinated Zhu Yi.
They deserve death.
I
hereby order
troops sent at once
to encircle Shanhua Valley.
I want
the whole valley
razed to the ground.
Yes.
Sir.
Something happened in the capital?
Zhu Yi came to me
with a lead
on my birth parents
and asked me to spare his life.
That's good.
I told you so.
I knew you'd find your family.
When the time comes,
take us with you.
We'll find a place to farm
and live a good life all the same.
Chang'an.
I have something to handle.
Go back to Shanhua Valley.
Sir.
You haven't recovered.
Let me handle it instead.
Don't be scared, birdie.
I'll fix you right up
and give you two new joints.
Birth details?
Sir.
The Noble Consort gave birth
before entering the palace.
Yun Zhanpeng abandoned the baby
in a mass grave.
On the baby's shoulder
was a hibiscus-shaped brand.
Han Jin.
Why meet me here all of a sudden?
Why couldn't we talk in the palace?
Zhao?
It's you.
Next time you want to see me,
come to the palace anytime.
I've already given the order.
No one will stop you.
You are my mother?
You know?
When did you find out?
When you were punished at the gate,
I saw the mark on your shoulder.
I put it there with...
Zhao, are you angry with me?
The moment I knew you were my son,
I stopped them
from hitting you again.
How are your wounds?
Let me see.
Who's my father?
Han Jin?
What about the Crown Prince?
Who did you have him with?
You and Qingyan
are brothers.
You swapped
the Crown Prince
with Yun Shao.
Han Jin didn't mean to kill the Empress.
It was an accident.
Your Highness.
You really are something.
You toyed the royal family for fools.
Even your own sons
are pawns in your climb to the throne.
That's not true.
Zhao, listen to me.
I never meant to use you.
Zhao, listen.
The day you were born,
word came that Han Jin was dead.
My father forced me into the palace.
I begged them
to find you a good home.
But they told me
you'd died.
Zhao.
Don't be angry.
I'll make it up to you.
Fine.
How will you make it up to me?
Tell me.
I'll give you
anything you want.
Fine.
I want
the throne.
[Prince of Xin'an's Residence]
Your Highness, we're here.
This is one of his men.
At the border,
he already has a ten-year-old son.
Are you sure
he still wants Qingyan and me
as his sons?
To the Crown Prince's.
Yes.
Let's go.
[Prince of Xin'an's Residence]
Mother Consort.
Why come so late?
What is it?
Han Jin snuck back four months ago.
His troops
are almost here.
There's no need for that.
Once Father dies,
I'll inherit the throne.
I don't need him anymore.
Qingyan.
What if Han Jin
is planning a rebellion?
A rebellion?
Didn't you say
you two were bound
by unshakable love,
and all he did was for me?
Are you mocking me?
I wouldn't dare.
Qingyan.
I only have you and your brother now.
You two need to stand together.
If you trust him that much,
then go to him.
Qingyan.
What's with that attitude?
What about you?
For eighteen years,
you never claimed me as your own.
Since I was old enough to understand,
the palace tongues questioned who I was.
Every day,
I live on edge,
unable to sleep,
dreading that one day
you'll have a son of your own
and cast me aside.
I care for you with all my heart.
How can you say that?
Care for me?
That was control.
What I ate or drank,
everyone I spoke to,
had to follow your will.
One misstep,
and I have failed you.
But with Pei Zhao?
Look at how you acted.
He won't even smile at you.
Yet you act like his lapdog,
wagging your tail at him.
Mind your tongue.
You'd never slap him so.
You'd only say,
"My dear Zhao,
you're so much better than Qingyan."
Qingyan.
Did I just...
Mother Consort.
I'll take my leave.
Qingyan, answer me.
If Han Jin
turns on his own sons,
what will you do?
You should worry about my brother first.
Han Jin will attack Shanhua Valley.
He gave the order himself.
He wants
the whole valley
razed to the ground.
You stay here
and protect everyone.
I'll draw them away.
Let me.
I know these mountain paths.
Lord Pei still isn't back.
Madam Yun.
I'll draw them away.
Chang'an, no.
Don't worry.
Those thugs
are no match for me.
Chang'an.
Stop it.
- Stop.
Freeze.
Ji Chang'an.
Shame on you.
Come here.
Guard Ji.
Brother Chang'an.
Run.
Whoever runs fastest
gets a reward from me.
Go.
My Lord's birth details
can't be lost.
Where are the others?
There are no others.
Just me.
Good.
You asked for the hard way.
Get him.
♪A cold blade gleams by the window♪
The hard way
it is!
♪A wisp of longing haunts the air♪
♪A lone boat rests on the misty river♪
♪That promise lies sealed with my sword♪
♪I turn to find the world in snow♪
♪Fated destiny ties from bygone life♪
♪Longing for one beloved flows on♪
♪I can't let go of the verses lost
across this vast land♪
♪Yet I let go of that fleeting light
within your eyes♪
- Chang'an.
Chang'an.
His hands
were covered in chilblains,
too stiff to even make a fist.
The year Lord Pei became commander,
he issued a new rule.
Anyone with a useful skill
could apply to the Fengyi Guard.
[Seven Years Ago]
[Fengyi Bureau]
Go.
Stay back.
Move.
Hear me?
Go.
Get lost.
[Fengyi Bureau]
You again?
Get lost.
[Fengyi Bureau]
♪A cold blade gleams by the window♪
♪Candle tears harden into frost♪
♪Moon shadows flicker and sway♪
♪A wisp of longing haunts the air♪
♪A lone boat rests on the misty river♪
♪That promise lies sealed with my sword♪
♪I turn to find the world in snow♪
♪Fated destiny ties from bygone life♪
♪Longing for one beloved flows on♪
♪I can't let go of the verses lost
across this vast land♪
♪Yet I let go of that fleeting light
within your eyes♪